[music]
[Instructor] Our game
is almost complete now.
So, when we pick up the Powerup,
we can hit the enemy off the scene,
and then it will generate new enemies,
but the problem is,
we only have one Powerup,
and so when our Powerup goes away
we have no way of actually
defeating these enemies unless
we outsmart them by...
getting them to fall
off of the platform.
We're going to create
a new Powerup
every time we start a new wave.
In our SpawnManager Script,
we're actually going to declare
a new public GameObject
for our Powerup.
And now we need to make sure
that this reference is assigned
in our Editor.
So now in Unity,
if we select our Spawn Manager,
you can see
that we have an empty
Game Object for our Powerup Prefab
so make sure you go down
to your Project window under Assets
in your Prefabs folder.
Drag the Powerup
and then back
in our SpawnManager Script,
in our line of code
where we keep track
of when all of the enemies are gone,
and create new enemies,
we'll "Instantiate()"
a new "powerupPrefab."
Fortunately, we created a method
to generate random spawn
positions so we can just use
that again,
and then we'll just make
sure to set the rotation
of our powerupPrefab.
One thing that you could
do just to clean this up a bit more
is you could just make
a spawnPowerup() method
if you wanted to, and then every time
you wanted to create
a new Powerup, you can just
call that method instead,
but, for now, this one
line of code is fine.
And then just to test and see
that our Powerup spawning
works properly,
we'll delete our Powerup
from the scene,
Play our game,
and now we spawn the enemy,
and we didn't spawn a Powerup
so that's a problem.
I actually have well that's pretty lucky
but that wasn't exactly
what we wanted to do.
Let's see what we did
wrong in our Spawn Manager.
Ahh, so when we start the game,
we create a new EnemyWave
but we don't actually create
a new Powerup so we'll take
this line of code,
and we'll copy it...
so that in our Start() method
we also create
a new random position
for our powerupPrefab.
So now in our game,
if we try and get to our Powerup.
Let's see, can we make it.
Enemy fell off anyways,
got the Powerup.
Another Powerup spawns and there you go.
And then both enemies fall.
And then three enemies and two Powerups.
What you're going to do is
in your SpawnManager Script
you're going to create
a new public GameObject
for your Powerup Prefab.
In your Start() method,
you're going to Instantiate() a new
Powerup Prefab, and you're going to use
the GenerateSpawnPosition()
method once again so we get
a random position
for our Powerup
and then also in our Update() method
when we create a new EnemyWave
we'll create another
Powerup so that we can use
it in case we need it.
So, now it's your turn.
[music]